CARLOS D. MORA MORENO

ODEVENTER, THE NETHERLANDS · → +31 (0) 618 94 77 97 CARLOS@MORAMORENO.COM



Delivering new technologies in benefit of the society is my passion. My experience as a researcher in industry and academia has prepared me to react to the technological challenges facing the digital age. I manage a project focusing on the development of predictive models to better understand and improve a sustainable energy solution. My most recent results explain a decade-long problem about geometric constraints.

Values: Reliability, transcendence, innovation and pursuit of excellence, responsibility, respect,

personal development

Competencies: Analytical mind, attention to detail, leadership, proactivity, persistency, reliability,

multiculturality

Nationality: Mexican
Date of birth: 20/09/1990

EXPERIENCE

2017 - present Ph.D. Candidate at Eindhoven University of Technology

- **Main project:** Development of mathematical models to predict and reduce heat transport in fusion plasma reactors
- Skills / duties:
 - Perform 5-D numerical simulations in high performance computers
 - Program data analysis routines using modern languages
 - 'Big data' approach for analysis of terabytes of turbulence simulations
 - Build models, then test and validate their performance
 - Deliver engaging presentations
 - Write research proposals and reports
 - Prepare novel scientific publications
 - Manage multi-national collaborative tasks 2017

Research Associate at UK Atomic Energy Authority

- **Main project:** Develop experimental scenarios to test the capabilities of a new magnetic coil configuration of a fusion plasma reactor
- Skills / duties:
 - Solve 2-D magnetic equilibrium equations using a dedicated MATLAB package
 - Calculate magnetic coil interaction matrices
 - Devise the transitions between magnetic equilibria
 - Determine the viability of experimental scenarios
- Experiments ran successfully during device commissioning

2015 - 2016 Diagnostics Engineer at TAE technologies and spin-off Plasmatech

- **Main project:** Characterisation of impurity losses in a linear plasma device using Doppler spectroscopy
- Skills / duties:
 - Hands-on maintenance of experimental setup
 - Development of data acquisition routines
 - Support to lead scientists during experimental campaigns
 - o Involvement in discussion of physical results
 - Experience in a multi-physics, engineering and industrial environment
 - Result: Thesis on the main project

EDUCATION

2017 - present (est. May 2022)

Ph.D. in Applied Physics

Eindhoven University of Technology · Max Planck Institute for Plasma Physics

- Specialisation in Science and Technology of Nuclear Fusion
- In collaboration with the institute hosting the most advanced device of its type:
 Wendelstein 7-X
- Followed soft-skills training courses about communication, scientific integrity, project managing, writing workshops, and student supervision

2016 - 2017 Master of Science (with distinction) in Fusion Energy

University of York · UK Atomic Energy Authority

- Specialisation program to address the current energy demand with an innovative solution: Nuclear Fusion
- Focus on theoretical plasma physics and HPC computing
- One-year program with focus on research experience
- Awarded a scholarship from the Mexican Science and Technology Council

2014 International exchange experience

Universitat Autònoma de Barcelona

- Six months exchange program
- Followed courses:
 - Particle physics
 - Business organisation and management
 - Entrepreneurship

2009 - 2012 **Bachelor of Engineering Physics**

Universidad Autónoma Metropolitana - Azcapotzalco

- Assistant at the local plasma laboratory
- International exchange scholarship
- End-project scholarship

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

2015 - 2019

- Master thesis on plasma turbulence in stellarators
- Bachelor end-projects on turbulence saturation mechanisms in stellarators

SKILLS

Languages

Computer

- **Linux** · Preferred operating system (Suse)
- Vim · Preferred editor
- LaTeX · Publication-quality documents
- Bash, Make, ... · Daily scripting and development
- Microsoft Office · Where useful
- Git · For version control of virtually everything
- html, CSS · Used for this curriculum vitae (with markdown → Pandoc)

Programming

- **Python** · Numpy, scipy, cython, matplotlib, dask, pandas
- Jupyter · Lab and notebooks. Used for daily data analysis
- MATLAB · Data analysis, powerful toolset for engineers and scientists with full workflow experience
- Mathematica · Symbolic computing
- **SLURM** · Job manager used for cluster computing
- C++ · Used for side projects
- Fortran · HPC applications such as GENE
- Bash, Make · Experience with linux scripting and development
- MPI, OpenMP · Used for parallelisation for HPC

Q Deventer, The Netherlands · J +31 (0) 618 94 77 97 · ■ carlos@moramoreno.com

pdf version · txt version · html version · source